Dr. Khalifa: The mandatory test. [2:214]  Do you expect to enter Paradise without undergoing the same test as those before you? They suffered hardship and adversity, and were so shaken up, that the messenger ... (unintelligible), Sajjad, keep quiet. (unintelligible) [2:214]  ... They suffered hardship and adversity, and were so shaken up, that the messenger and those who believed with him said, "Where is God's victory?" Indeed, God's victory is always near. Okay, so the idea here is to worship God alone no matter what happens, under all circumstances. It's a matter of knowledge. You, you came to the conclusion that God is One, and He's the only Master, He's the only One that benefits your hearts. He's the only One who controls the minds and hearts of the people around you, He makes them love you or hate you or care about you or don't care. And with this knowledge, it doesn't matter what happens, adversity or happiness, or... It's a, it's a, it's a fixed definite knowledge. And you know that, it doesn't matter what happens. So, also, we are here for the test. And God wants to be proud of you and wants to show you off to the angels and say, look at My servant, he or she worships Me no matter what happens, without ever seeing Me. And this is the whole idea of our existence. And the end of the verse says, [2:214]  ... Indeed, God's victory is always near. It must be noted also here that after the tests, there is a final test. After the final test, there is absolutely, there is nothing but kingship on earth, as God promises, when you come to the conclusion that you worship God alone. And it takes a long time, the road is long and hard. It's a continuous struggle. But there will come a time when you are perfect worshipper of God alone. Then, there is no hardship. And we can see this in Sura 24:55. These are some of the verses that we must remember all the time. Page 243. The great promise. Because God promises those in verse 55. Page 243. [24:55] GOD promises those among you who believe and work righteousness, that He will make them kings on earth, as He did for those before them, and that He will establish for them the religion that He chose for them, and that He will substitute security in place of their fears. All this because they worship Me alone, without idolizing anything besides Me. If anyone disbelieves after this, then these are the wicked. (unintelligible), come and sit next to daddy. And Sajjad, sit next to mommy. Then, they will have no noise. Now, Jamila is free to roam there. See, this, this promise is true. Now, do you remember Job? Job had lots of hardships and adversities. But once he passed the test, he recovered, his health recovered, he recovered his family, and even twice as much. He recovered his wealth, and twice as much. So, he was under the test for as long as he needed to be tested, to prove himself. And the same is true with us. Also, we must think of adversity as a cleansing and polishing process. When you join the Oneness of God alone, you expect some trouble at the beginning. Because you're cleansing all the past sins, all the past errors. And this can be cleansed only by paying for them, in this world. So, all the adversity that you have at the beginning, you come, you come join this mosque, you're gonna have five or ten years of adversity. And this is because it's a polishing process. Polishing, you know how polishing goes. They take a piece of rock, and they put it in polishing machine. Very noisy. Chipping off pieces. But then what comes out is a beautiful gem. And that's what, what will come out after you go through the polishing process. Polishing is not easy. So, what I'm saying is that there is a final test. Also, if we look up Sura 65, verse 3 and 4. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: The verse is 4 or 5. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Page 401. Page 401. Verse 2, let's look verse 2 at the end of it. It says, [65:2]  ... Whoever observes righteousness towards GOD, He will create an exit for him. An exit of every problem. [65:3]  And provide for him whence he never expects. ... When you observe God, you sacrifice a job or a source of income, strictly for the sake of God, He will provide for you whence you never expect. And you better believe it. Sura, page 401. The end of verse 2. This is a verse I wanted to remember. [65:2]  ... Whoever observes righteousness towards GOD, He will create an exit for him. [65:3]  And provide for him whence he never expects. Anyone who trusts in GOD, God will suffice him. God always carries out His decisions. ... You have come to the conclusion that God is the King, the Absolute Ruler of the universe. And He will carry out His promises and His decisions. You just, you just have to believe it. You must have absolute confidence in it. Tomorrow, there is a mandatory law, insurance law. And we have, quite a few of us have decided that we have insurance with God. But if you are with God, you have the best insurance. And you just have to believe that. That nothing will happen to you, when you have insurance with God. This, this is the insurance. The difference between the insurance companies, and God's insurance is that in God's insurance, you don't have anything happen to you, to your car, to your health. With the, with the insurance companies, you will have the accidents, and the insurance company will pay for you. You have the agony of the insurance, of the accident, and the inconvenience of losing the car from you, or having an operation. And the companies will pay. But you just have to have the confidence that when you have insurance with God, nothing will happen to you. Also, you must know that if God wants to get you, He'll get you, whether you have insurance or not. There's, God says, they cannot escape from Me. That's what He said. You deserve a pinch or a little accident, or a little sickness. Dr. Khalifa: You can't get away, not by an insurance company. Yes. A man: This (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: Yes? Dr. Khalifa: When you have to, then you have to. We will not buy insurance unless we have to. But, but it appears that God is already taking care of us, because the law enforcement (unintelligible) the prosecutors are all protesting the law, and they're making an official case out of it to, they say, they will not enforce it. They don't, they don't want to enforce it. So, I called the Civil Liberties Union myself, and I told them this contradicts our religious beliefs, and everything, and they didn't do anything about it. So, we will not buy insurance until we have to. Because the Quran says, if you have to eat pork, or drink wine, or do anything, if you have to, without being malicious or deliberate, then you're not committing a sin. But what I'm saying is, when God says, And provide for you whence you never expect, you must, you must know that. You must have that confidence. If you have the slightest doubt, it will not work. And this insurance business, we, we're in it, we've been in a long time. I mean, we had that conviction to the extent, I told you about our friend Tariq, when the guy says, what insurance, who's your insurance with? And he said, I have insurance with God, (unintelligible) His phone number. He didn't, he just, he didn't, he wasn't thinking, I mean, it was the natural question coming afterwards, but then of course, he, he was stunned. Because he had a pencil in his hand and a paper, he was ready to write the phone number. It was at tune-up place, where Tariq's car was a little bit, the fender was (unintelligible) somebody (unintelligible). So, God always carries out His decisions. He is the Absolute Ruler. He runs this country. It's not Ronald Reagan who runs the country, or the government, or any government, anywhere. God runs everything. If you go to the end of verse 4, it says, [65:4]  ... Whoever observes righteousness towards GOD, God will make everything easy for him. Everything will go easy for you. You will not suffer any hardship. There's absolutely no humiliation for the servants of God. You go apply for a job, and you'll be the boss, because your soul takes over the place, and you'll see them running to serve you. They may not realize it, but you'll see it. [65:4]  ... Whoever observes righteousness towards GOD, God will make everything easy for him. This is God's promise, as documented here, in His final message. So, we go back now to page 23, about hardship as a mandatory test. Over and over we see people who are immensely wealthy on the TV, and they're complaining about unhappiness, Dr. Khalifa: how unhappy they, they are. A woman: Rashad. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: Is there an explanation for (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A woman: I don't know (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right. All this severe problems, earthquakes hurricanes, floods, all these are punishments, punishments and tests because all these things are absolutely controlled by God There is a statement that will answer your question. It's in Sura, I believe 64, let's look up 64. It's Sura 64, plus or minus 2 Suras, so, I'm gonna find it for you. Yeah, 11, verse 11. It says, [64:11]  No disaster strikes except in accordance with God's will. ... This is, this is a law. [64:11]  No disaster strikes except in accordance with God's will. ... No, no pain, no disaster, nothing happens except by personal decree from God because it is not simple. It's not, it's not easy to, to get a painful headache, for example. It has to be a personal decree from God, that God will sign. (unintelligible) come and sit here, be comfortable. Get a pillow or something. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Does this answer your question, Diana? Diana: Yes Diana: I, I, I saw (unintelligible), I had heard also that the floods had only affected a certain income, income, Diana: they'd only affected the wealthiest people (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Diana: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Well, God is angry. It's true. Every drop of water is measured. Everything in this world is measured. Every piece of ice that fell on Denver will give them miserable time. Dr. Khalifa: It was measured, yeah. Diana: They did say also that it's almost like the Nile. It's raining it's gonna make that land even more fertile. (unintelligible) The rich will move out because (unintelligible) Diana: I mean, there isn't maybe money in (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Everything is planned. Every, the minutest detail is very carefully planned. Alhamdu Lillah. Nothing is coincidental or haphazard. Nothing. As individuals, as nations, as a world. Just think, every drop of water is measured, exactly where it goes, where it's gonna fall, how many inches from an ant that's crawling on the ground. That's right. Dr. Khalifa: Okay Carl, do you wanna take recipients of charity from 215 to 218? Carl: Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem [2:215]  They ask you about charity: say, "Charity shall go to the parents, the relatives, the orphans, the poor, and the alien." Any righteous work you do, GOD is fully aware thereof. [2:216]  Fighting may be forced upon you, though you dislike it. But you may dislike something which is actually good for you, and you may like something which is actually bad for you. GOD knows while you do not know. [2:217]  They ask you about the desecration of the Sacred Months by fighting therein: say, "Fighting during the Sacred Months is sacrilege. But repelling the people from the path of GOD and disbelieving in Him and in the sacredness of the Sacred Mosque (Masjid), and evicting the people therefrom, are all worse sacrileges in the sight of GOD. Oppression is worse than murder." They will continue to fight you until they revert you from your religion, if they could. Those who revert from their religion, and die as disbelievers, have wasted their works in this life and in the Hereafter. They have deserved Hell, wherein they abide forever. [2:218]  As for those who believe, emigrate and strive in the cause of GOD, they have deserved God's mercy. GOD is Forgiver, Merciful. There is two different subjects here. 215 talks about the charity, and it tells us specifically that the charity first goes to those that are closest to us, to those that we're most responsible for, our parents and our relatives. And the next are those that, that really need economic help, or don't have someone else to rely on, the orphans, and the poor, and then the alien. Carl: And... Dr. Khalifa: So, this is a carefully, that we, we are given the details of how charity should be distributed. First, goes to the parents if they need it. If they don't need it, then to your relatives. In other words, each takes care of his own. And each one takes care of his own, there will be no misery in the world. If the relatives are rich, then you find orphans, children, children who have no parents, one or two parents are gone. Dr. Khalifa: And then any poor people, and then the alien in this world. Carl: So, any righteous work you do, GOD is fully aware of it. And it seems that charity is more than just economic help. It can be any kind of help, and any righteousness of, doing what is right in this world toward other people. Even if it's simply politeness or anything we try to do to make the, the world better, treat the other people as we'd like to be treated, or be merciful toward the people around us. Then, God is, is because we want to express God's mercy. We want, we desire God's forgiveness and God's mercy, and these qualities, and by showing our appreciation, we desire for and we express Carl: toward the world around us. Martha: (unintelligible) Carl: Martha. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) from another town (unintelligible) A woman: How about E.T.? Dr. Khalifa: People are passing, passing by. Carl: And the next subject is on fighting which I take to mean basically in a war type of situation, though it may be, well, when we think of fighting, we think of taking up arms, of, of violence rather than simply arguing (unintelligible) So, at another level, it could be simply not giving in to, to any kind of oppressions, Carl: which may be economic or political or social, but... No, I, no, I have to put (unintelligible) The only, there's only one reason in Quran for fighting. And it has to do with the freedom to worship God alone. That's it. There's absolutely no other reason for fighting, only if it's gonna interfere with your freedom of practicing the worship of God alone. And oppression, meaning trying to impose any, any view, religious view on you, or to prevent you from practicing your religion. Throughout the Quran, the reason, the only reason for fighting is fighting might be imposed upon you, like somebody comes and say, Dr. Khalifa: hey, don't pray. You cannot pray. They issue a law that you cannot pray. A man: But if, if your country gets into war with another country and you're required to go and fight, like you're drafted or anything? Dr. Khalifa: No, you don't fight because of land. If you're drafted, ... A man: No, no, you can't (unintelligible).  Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the other country is here to make you not believe in God, A man: Yeah, if they are attacking us, ... Dr. Khalifa: like if Russia comes to invade this country for the purpose of turning everybody into an atheist, then that's in the cause of God. The only fighting is in the cause of God. It must be in the cause of God. So, whatever, whatever the, there are unforeseeable reasons or circumstances. But fighting for land, or because of borders, or because of country, it's all a waste of life. Dr. Khalifa: And because God did not create these borders. He didn't create visas and passports. A man: What if you're forced to defend yourself and somebody else wants to drive you away from your, your own land? A man: You have to fight, also. Or you just, you know, run away. Dr. Khalifa: Well, the self... Dr. Khalifa: The self defense. But it, it isn't because of God.  It is... Dr. Khalifa: to think about it. A man: Yeah. Yeah. A man: I mean, if they, what it says about evicting you from your houses, or you evict them from where they evicted you. A man: You do not (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: [2:191]  ... evict them whence they evicted you. ... Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A man: You know, if they're simply fighting not, they're not perceiving religious reasons, they're probably perceiving grabbing land, or political differences. Dr. Khalifa: Did we, did we go through the rules of war yet? Because that will explain it more. A woman: 190. It's... Dr. Khalifa: Did we go through that? Dean Majul: About aggression. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yeah, we did. Yeah, we did. Dean Majul: You spoke of aggression. That wars are only justified, all wars must be defensive. And we discussed that earlier. Dr. Khalifa: Self-defense, yeah. Dean Majul: And offense. Dr. Khalifa: But in those rules of war, they say, [2:191]  ... Do not fight them at the Sacred Mosque (Masjid), unless they attack you therein. ... If we're sitting here worshipping God alone, and somebody comes and says, hey, you can't, Dr. Khalifa: you can't practice Islam here, or something, you know, this is where we have to fight them. A woman: I want to hear everybody cry. Dean Majul: You'd be surprised. Anything can happen. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A woman: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: We just, we happen to have a formidable army around this building anyway, as you know. Brother Abdullah is visiting us from Seattle. And he's, he's one rare person who comes because he, he, he were leery of the Hadith. So, he came to see us just because we believe in the Quran alone. But anyway, what I wanna tell you is that people try to deface this sign out there, and, and, twice, because they felt miserable every time. So, there are invisible forces around us here. We don't need to do anything. This age is an age of mental, mental debate, rather than swords and fighting. Dr. Khalifa: Anyway, we can't fight because of land, over land or money, or, and, unless you're attacked, anyway. A man: What about (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Joining is something, and fighting is something else. Dr. Khalifa: I mean, they join the armed forces, but they don't fight, but it's like a job. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: It's a waste of life. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: The job is a means of supporting your, to earn an honest living. A man: If you, if you join anything and you simply earn a living for something, Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: if it's part of an institution that's involved in something, it's not... A man: Yeah, but you don't know what else is involved. Dr. Khalifa: Well, you don't earn your living selling liquor, for example, which is breaking God's law. A man: But suppose you went to work... Dr. Khalifa: But he's asking about joining the armed forces. Dr. Khalifa: Well, if you joined the armed forces and there's no war, it's just like any job. A man: But suppose your government gets in a war with another country and you... Dr. Khalifa: That's when you have to make a decision whether this is because of God or not. Because of God, you pick a fight? Dr. Khalifa: If it's in the cause of God, that will do it. A man: Well, suppose you're working for a big company and they're producing something that, you know, like, it's... Well, or, say, napalm or chemical weapons. A man: You know, maybe you're not directly involved in the manufacturing, but you (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: That's, if there is no war, it's perfectly all right, because the Quran says, prepare for war, prepare the maximum power that you have. Be prepared. But war itself is, as, aggression is forbidden. That's breaking God's law. So, joining the armed forces or making weapons or anything that is not war is perfectly all right. Dr. Khalifa: If it is war, then you have to make a decision if it is in the cause of God or not. A man: So, it's okay to have nuclear arms race? Dr. Khalifa: That's right. You bet. Dr. Khalifa: If we, if we didn't have nuclear weapons in this country, you can be sure Russia will be here in a week. A man: What, what about the idea that, Dr. Khalifa: Effectively over. A man: what about the idea that we trusted God to protect us? Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but God orders you to make weapons. A man: But if the, you know, if we really, it's like the insurance (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: No. A man: If you really trusted God, He, He sent you weapons, Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: the bombs. Dr. Khalifa: When you trust in God A man: why would He liberate them in the sky? Dr. Khalifa: When you trust in God, you follow His commandments. One of His commandments is, prepare the maximum power you can muster. This is a, a verse in the Quran. You wanna see it? (unintelligible) I think it's in Sura 9. But I wanna refer to the, the index. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, I, I meant to talk to you about this once before because you said, trust in God and don't make any weapons. A man: Preemptive strike which is attacking first. Dr. Khalifa: Hello, hello, hello. A man: They call it preemptive strike. They didn't say attacking. Dean Majul: And that's 4:41. Dean Majul: 39:41 A man: (unintelligible) Dean Majul: I'm not so sure. A man: It's a matter of strategy. A man: Sura 9 Dean Majul: Sura 9, verse 41 Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, no, there is a more straightforward verse. Dean Majul: It says, Dean Majul: [9:41] ... readily mobilize, ... A man: It's page 112. Dr. Khalifa: There's a straightforward commandment to prepare the maximum power. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Sura 8, verse 60. Sura 8, verse 60. This is a commandment, you shall. It says, you, this is page 124, verse 6 0, 60. [8:60]  You shall prepare for them all the force and equipment you can muster in order to deter the enemies of GOD, and your enemies, as well as others you are not aware of while GOD knows them. Anything you expend in the cause of GOD will be repaid to you, without the least injustice. It's a very straightforward commandment, it says, prepare. You must, you must always have a deterring force. Dr. Khalifa: So, it is, you trust in God, but you follow what He says. You know, it's not... A man: It says, 20 can defeat 200. And take your time. Dr. Khalifa: That's right. A man: There was an early battle in which the, the Muslims were greatly outnumbered. Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah. A man: And, and there was a chance (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: That's, that's another one, that's another one. Dr. Khalifa: But the battle of Badr, look it up, look it up in the encyclopedia Britannica. A man: Badr. Dr. Khalifa: And they looked at it from the strategic point of view, the logistic point of view, the, the numbers of needs (unintelligible) And they tried to analyze it militarily and this doesn't make sense. Dr. Khalifa: The Muslims defeated the disbelievers. Dean Majul: Also, the battle of Yarmuk, when they beat, when they beat the Byzantine, Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Dean Majul: they were outnumbered. Dean Majul: And in the battle of Qadisiyyah against the Persians, Dr. Khalifa: Right. Dean Majul: the best army in the world. Dr. Khalifa: Now those were... Dean Majul: Full Persians. Dr. Khalifa: Those were actual battles where the Muslims were outnumbered 10 to 1. Dr. Khalifa: But we're told in Quran that the angels were fighting beside Muslims. A man: We have enough weapons now to destroy 200 (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Good. A man: Do we need to go anywhere? Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Well, they are, they are, they are having the practical means to nullify (unintelligible), Laser (unintelligible) A man: And they can't satellite (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: But, well, back to Carl. Let's listen to Carl. Carl: [2:191]  ... Oppression is worse than murder. ... Dr. Khalifa: instead of the soul. Carl: It's... It's an attempt to manipulate somebody's mind and heart. And... To Carl: make other people follow one's own material desires. And Carl: whoever is (unintelligible) Dean Majul: May I add, may I add, add something to that as a revision? Dean Majul: It's not just that they're trying to change your mind. Dean Majul: But to make you revert to a situation of unbelief. Carl: Yes. Dean Majul: In other words, the Muslims now have come, they've arrived at the truth. All right? Dean Majul: And for you to go from truth back to unbelief, Carl: Yes. Dean Majul: that is what our Ustaz is saying is Dr. Khalifa: Murder of the soul. Dean Majul: Murder of the soul. It's not a matter of just changing your belief. Dean Majul: But it's going back to unbelief, which is terrible. Carl: Yeah. Dean Majul: And Quran says many times, once you have the belief, many people will try to let you revert to unbelief. So, that is a, it's terrible because the punishment for, the punishment for unbelief after belief is greater than just unbelief from beginning to end. Dean Majul: I think Quran says that too, a few times. Carl: Yeah, it says it in the next... Dean Majul: Does it say so? I'm sorry. Carl: It says, [2:217]  ... Those who revert from their religion, and die as disbelievers, have wasted their works in this life and in the Hereafter. They have deserved Hell, wherein they abide forever. [2:218]  And those who believe, emigrate and strive in the cause of GOD, ... So, it's telling me I think that if we are oppressed and we can't fight them, it's better to get up and leave and go someplace where we can follow or obey God's commandment. To write, to, I guess it's telling us to fight if we can, if not to, to try to get away from that situation. Carl: [2:218]  ... GOD is Forgiver, Merciful. Dean Majul: Now, this, this is very interesting verse because people have pointed out many times. I think they, they interpret this verse out of context. "How can oppression or persecution be worse than the murder?" They say. But actually, if you read the whole thing, I think what it means is this: Dean Majul: In the long run, going to Hell Dr. Khalifa: is a lot worse. Dean Majul: It's worse than the murder. Dean Majul: I think oppression, I think this is what it means. Carl: If you die in the cause of God,... Dean Majul: But some people don't seem to care about this. Dr. Khalifa: Oppression to change your belief, it's like taking you out of Heaven, putting you in Hell. Dr. Khalifa: It's a lot worse than murder. Dean Majul: I don't understand why the enemies of Islam have used this against (unintelligible) Carl: We have to take this in conjunction Carl: with the other verses that tell us about dying in the cause of God. Dean Majul: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Diana has a question. Diana: With that, Ok, would something (unintelligible) in court. Diana: I mean, we're here in America, but we have to take our, our, our law here and use it here. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Diana: So, you were proud of (unintelligible) because you (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Well, in this country is fanatic about religious freedom. Diana: Yeah, but not (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, legal. Yeah. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: I mean, for example, zoning laws don't apply to you. You can have a church anywhere you want. Dr. Khalifa: Zoning laws do not apply. Diana: (unintelligible) Diana: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Tax laws. Diana: You know like, (unintelligible) a lot of (unintelligible) a lot of (unintelligible) Diana: for (unintelligible) looking out Dr. Khalifa: But who needs them? Diana: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, who needs them? If you have God on your side, God manipulates their minds and their hearts. So, when they are prejudiced, they are only hurting themselves. Dr. Khalifa: So, they have, they have a specific situation. A woman: Well, no. In fact, someone is, someone did attack you. A woman: You felt that it was something, you know, (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Oh, oh. A woman: And (unintelligible) you couldn't. Would you be able to use this in court? (unintelligible) Carl: No. Diana: Ok. But it was self-defense. So, you didn't... Dr. Khalifa: But no, but you can't... No, you can't get just like that. A man: Yeah, you have to be accepted first, though. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: You have to be (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right. Dr. Khalifa: No, I mean, somebody criticize your religion and you kill him! Dr. Khalifa: That doesn't even, even the Quran will not advocate that. A man: I think, the fact, also (unintelligible) murdered (unintelligible) A man: who were seen in Mecca, who were oppressed by the, by the (unintelligible) of Satan. A man: And the one who did it immigrate, the one were being encouraged by this immigration were... Dr. Khalifa: You're looking at one right now. I can't say the things I'm saying in Saudi Arabia or Egypt. I'll be killed. The things I'm saying now. They're saying, I mean, (unintelligible) by, but even the people here in this country from over there when we tell them, "worship God alone, the Quran, the (unintelligible), believe God", Dr. Khalifa: they fight you violently. Because you're attacking their god, their idol. A man: And I think it doesn't apply now but I'm saying also in (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Immigration means you go to the spot where you worship God alone really without interference. Dr. Khalifa: You want to immigrate, when you're in a place where you cannot worship God alone really, you move out, Dean Majul: get out Dr. Khalifa: go to a place where you can worship God alone. A man: (unintelligible) make up (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A man: (unintelligible) in California. I mean, (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A man: (unintelligible)  Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible), yes. A man: This is the extreme of what you can (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: In Christian, Christians. A man: (unintelligible) TV everyday. Dr. Khalifa: People will abuse the religion all the time. But you, you are all believers in God alone, the Quran alone. But you cannot say this overseas in the so-called Muslim countries. You cannot say it. And if, if they feel that you will have any influence Dr. Khalifa: doing this, they will actually put you in trial and kill you. That's a threat. A man: Did you say a moment ago that the tax laws don't apply here? Dr. Khalifa: Tax laws, churches are examples of tax, tax laws. They don't pay taxes. A man: Oh, I thought, I thought you meant that as a Muslim, you don't have to pay taxes. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) very good, very good. Dean Majul: We don't know if the United States will become Muslim in 24 hours. A man: (unintelligible) Dean Majul: No, but we're gonna save them. A man: Oh. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Religious organizations. Religious... Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Dean Majul: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Dean Majul: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: You're finished, Carl? Carl: I think so. Carl: Is there something else, you mean? Dr. Khalifa: Any questions on the, you see the subtitle, Submit to the Omniscient. It's a very important principle in, in Quran. [2:216]  ... you may like something which is actually bad for you. ... or [2:216]  ... you may dislike something which is actually good for you, ... You go apply for a job, the worshipper of God alone, and you don't get the job. Why? Because it's not good for you. This is why you go to apply to jobs and you, you don't care if you're gonna get it or not because you know that God will give you the job that's good for you. You submit to God. You submit to the Omniscient. Omniscient means, He knows what circumstances you will exist under every job you're applying for. So, what you do when you're applying for a job is you knock on all the doors and God will open the one that is good for you. So, when you don't get a job, it is not something, something that you dislike it, [2:216]  ... But you may dislike something which is actually good for you, ... It's good for you that you didn't take their job. And you can think of a million things that you may like which is bad for you and you may like something which is bad for you. Well, that's an, that's an important principle that you are taking advantage of the fact that your Lord is Omniscient, and knows exactly what is best for you. Intoxicants and Gambling Prohibited* Dr. Khalifa: They're all human. That's a (unintelligible) A man: (unintelligible) A man: [2:219]  They ask you about intoxicants and gambling: say, "There is gross evil in them, and some benefits for the people. However, their evil outweighs their benefit." They ask you of what to give as charity: say, "The excess." GOD thus clarifies the revelations for you, that you may reflect, [2:220]  upon this life and the Hereafter. They ask you about the orphans: say, "The best thing is to bring them up as righteous individuals. If you mix their property with yours, you shall treat them as members of your family." GOD is fully aware who the wicked are, and who the righteous are. Had GOD willed, He could have decreed harsher rules. GOD is Almighty, Wise. But verse, there is a commandment in verse 219 and it's straightforward commandment. God is forbidding us to have intoxicants and to, to do gambling. A man: And God said, there is evil in this, having intoxicants or doing gambling. Dr. Khalifa: Tonight is a perfect night for this law. A man: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Because people are out there imbibing and, and drinking, but it's going out of style. While we are studying God's message, which each one of you gets a hundred time the reward tonight. Dr. Khalifa: Because people are out there breaking God's law with intoxicants and gambling. A new lottery is out. A man: Okay, now... Dr. Khalifa: They call it lucky seven Dr. Khalifa: Started today or yesterday. Ahamd: Thursday. Dr. Khalifa: Huh? Started Thursday? A man: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, Ahmad know. He sells, he sells the tickets. Dr. Khalifa: The lottery is a perfect example of breaking God's law and what it does to you. A man: We got a real bad one in the mail today. A man: (unintelligible) or something like that. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A man: "You, Mr. and Mrs. Johnson have won a million dollars." Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A man: (unintelligible) Audience: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: I wouldn't send it back. A man: Okay, now in this verse it says, A man: [2:219]  ... "There is gross evil in them, and some benefits for the people. ... A man: What could be these benefits? Like, you know, earning money from these things? Dr. Khalifa: I mean, it says, (unintelligible) farmers, farmers who plant the grapes A man: Ok. Can you... A man: Okay, can you... Dr. Khalifa: See, the Quran is... A man: Consider that selling these things, for example. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A woman: Like (unintelligible) A man: Selling wine or, you know, that makes profit, that brings profit to you. Dr. Khalifa: The Quran, the Quran is very a mystery. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, this is a good point. The Quran is accurate. And the Quran cannot, the Quran acknowledges the fact that some people, farmers plant the grapes and sell them. And there are lots of people who have jobs because of wine and so forth. So, that cannot, that has to be stated. But God says that they have more evil than the benefits. [2:219]  ... their evil outweighs their benefit." ... Dr. Khalifa: Therefore, if we follow God's law, we have to eliminate the gross evil. A man: (unintelligible) Dean Majul: May I add something? I do not deny that this is one of the meanings that it can give employment benefits to hundreds of people (unintelligible) as, as a rather Arab saying. It also means something else, over and above. For example, I noticed that in certain cases, when some people are feeling bad and so on, they give them a shot, a [ __ ], you know. It could all mean that also. You know, to put them up is very cold. It can help them temporarily. But in the long run, it's bad if it becomes a habit. Dean Majul: I think there's a possibility. Dr. Khalifa: You're talking about medicine, as I remember. Dean Majul: Yes, yeah, It's small point, it's given in small quantity. Dean Majul: And so, this is a tear that if... A man: That was a good point. Dean Majul: I would like that receipt. Dean Majul: I mean that description. Audience: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) You're breaking, you're breaking God's law. And you pay a high price for it. And we have, the best illustration is, is Arizona and the lottery. Arizona instituted the lottery to make some money and they were never poorer. Never. The year they introduced the lottery, the copper went bad. Dr. Khalifa: And the state had a hundred million dollars deficit. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: A hundred million dollars deficit. Something that never happened in the history of Arizona. So, from the time they started the lottery, they have been poor and they had deficits. They had to have freezing of employment and cut down in budgets. And I worked for the state and I don't know what is happening in the state. So, on, on... And God does it in such a way that now the officials responsible for the lottery say, we have a hundred million dollars deficit. Can you imagine how much it would have been without the lottery? So, they, they, they never understand. They are not supposed to. But it is a fact. It's a fact of life that Arizona is poorer because of the lottery, and since the lottery started. And the same is true with us. If we are to break God's law and gamble in order to make money, we'll probably make ten thousand and then lose a hundred thousand somewhere else. It's the way God works. When you break His law, you have a, a blindfold Dr. Khalifa: put on you. A man: So, all these sweepstakes and contests they keep sending in the mail, is that the same thing? Dr. Khalifa: Exactly the same thing. Now, if they send and say you already won something, you didn't gamble, and they say, oh, this, they send it in, fine. Dr. Khalifa: Take it. (unintelligible) a gift from God. Dean Majul: Yeah, because you have not invested in anything. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly, you didn't go after it, you didn't apply for it, you didn't participate in it, but it came to you. Dean Majul: I know that's real money or (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right. Dr. Khalifa: However, I don't think you'll ever win a thing like that. God, when God wants to send you money, will send it to you legitimately. Dean Majul: It doesn't happen really. Dr. Khalifa: And very honest and straightforward way. Each one of us, by the way, have a number of dollars assigned to him or to her. There's no way you're gonna get any more. There's no way you're gonna get any less. Dr. Khalifa: You cannot escape from it. Dean Majul: Can I ask, can I ask a question? Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Dean Majul: It's a little bit off the subject, but related. My sister-in-law sent my wife last week a big package, you know, all sisters, as a gift. And my wife, in her enthusiasm, she opened and she threw the wrappings just to find out what was inside. It's all right. And as usual, I'm the garbage cleaner, and I pick up the this old papers, and I was going to crush them and put it in the, in the garbage can, or rather it is, whatever it is you have. Then, I saw that all the stamps on the cover, you know these ones, Dean Majul: all the stamps in the cover Dr. Khalifa: are not canceled. Dean Majul: were not canceled. Dean Majul: about five dollars. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Dean Majul: So, there are many possibilities. I personally took it as manna from heaven. Either, one possibility, I go, I cut the thing, and like a fool, go to the post office, ask my son to drive me, it's going to cost two or three dollars, and say, Mr. Postmaster, you people forgot to do it. Will you please cancel it? Or I give it to someone, and most probably (unintelligible) will get it. And anyhow, he has a girlfriend, he has to write to her too, so he'll use stamps. Or, I return it to my sister-in-law, Dean Majul: and tell her, use it for next year when you give us another... A man: Again. Dean Majul: Or, I use it for mailing. Or as Kathleen Lider would say, I put it in my stamp collection. That's (unintelligible) point of view. (unintelligible) This is something that happened that, that was, there are, it's a, somebody made a mistake. Dean Majul: What do you think? Dr. Khalifa: Well, you're putting me to the test. I would consider a gift from God to use it. Because the post office, I don't know, they, they went beyond the reasonable limits in their inflation, you know. I mean, if, if you look at the inflation of the post office, and inflation of, in the country, it was an average 10% in the last 10 years, but the post office went up like 100%. So, from that point of view, I disagree with the post office, and I would consider it a gift from God, Dr. Khalifa: I will take the stamps and use them. A man: But... Dr. Khalifa: They came to me. Yes. A man: Last week, there was a discussion that, it looks like that if you go to (unintelligible) take care and make any (unintelligible) A man: and get the extra money instead of, you know, A man: the right money. Dean Majul: some money. A man: So, I feel that... Dr. Khalifa: No, no, in that case, she is losing the money, because at the end of the day, she has to count the money, Dr. Khalifa: and account for everything. Dean Majul: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: If it's short, she will pay. Dean Majul: She pays (unintelligible) from her pocket. Dr. Khalifa: You've taken money from a person. Dr. Khalifa: That's taking money from a person. A man: (unintelligible) Dean Majul: No, it's not the same. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Well, it is not, it's... Dr. Khalifa: That's somebody who's really (unintelligible) Dean Majul: But at the same time, almost disapproves. Dr. Khalifa: We were, Dr. Khalifa: We were, well, two years ago, we were sending the packets, packets for less than a pound, a pound or less, for 23 cents. Dr. Khalifa: Now, it is 63 cents in two years. Dean Majul: Three, three times almost. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. So, that's 300% in three years, which is 100% per year. And that's way out of proportion. So, you're justifying when God sent you some un-cancelled stamps, in my opinion, you, you justify it in using them. Dr. Khalifa: And it's usually a very minor amount, anyway. Dean Majul: Well, it's in my, it's got to be my stamp album. Dr. Khalifa: That's my opinion, and God knows this. Dean Majul: But this happens naturally. A woman: Mã Shã Allãh Dean Majul: It just happens. A man: (unintelligible) A man: You know what happens. Dean Majul: Alhamdu Lillah. A man: Several times, I got the mail from the university. A man: This university mail, and I never stepped on it. Dean Majul: Yeah. A man: I cut it, and I put it, and I mailed, and... Dean Majul: Re. se it again. Because otherwise, it's gonna be destroyed. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Ok. A man: It's gonna be wasted. That's (unintelligible) Dean Majul: I'm sorry bring this up, but it's a problem to think about. And we can both think about. Dr. Khalifa: What? To me, I, I just look at the inflation of the post office and inflation in the country. I consider it an act of God that we're sent stamps un-, un-cancelled. Dr. Khalifa: Errol, back to you. Intoxicants and Gambling Errol: Okay. So much for that. Errol: The Quran says specifically intoxicants (unintelligible) does not say, wine. Dean Majul: No, no, intoxicant. Errol: Because (unintelligible) say, there is only Errol: it's only (unintelligible) wine. Dean Majul: That's another (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: A lot, a lot of people want to see white (unintelligible) and, you know, you shall not drink white (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: The words in the Quran imply all intoxicants, including marijuana and anything that describes or mentions (unintelligible) unless it's (unintelligible) (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: adversity Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: It wake you up. Errol: Ok. There is also a statement about the charity in the same verse, and, So, it, it tells us how much, how much charity we can give of our own, you know, money or whatever possession we have. And God says, [2:219]  ... "The excess." ... Errol: The one, the, the portion that we do not need for us. Dr. Khalifa: The necessities of life as I said. Errol: Right. Dr. Khalifa: In other words, you do not give away from your own necessities of life. A man: So,... Errol: Right. Errol: We give away the things that we do not need from the things that we (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: In other words, the charity begins at home. Errol: Next verse tells about the orphans and is, God orders, give the command to raise them up as a, as Muslims. And so we should give the same care for, to them, to the orphans that we give to our children. Errol: So, both our, our own children and the orphans, we have to raise them up as Muslims, like... Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)  Errol: And these two verses are very clear. And God, God shows His mercy again. It says here, He is so Merciful that He says, I could have made very, more harder commandments for you, but Errol: He is so Merciful, He makes it, He makes everything easy for us. A man: I just see the other one about the property. Errol: The property? A man: Yeah. A man: (unintelligible) Errol: Oh. Okay. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) does not consume their property. A man: That's right. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Errol: God tells us in the, in the other, in other Ayat, I cannot remember exact place, but tells us that we have to keep their property until they grow up, you know, Errol: they have the (unintelligible) to, yeah, their own judgement, so we have to give them back. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. You must be very careful not to take one penny out of the orphans' money. If you are entrusted with the money of the orphans, it's very, very bad, unless the person who is taking care of the orphans is very poor himself, and he takes a wage, for instance, for administering the money of the orphans, and, and, and the service to them. Dr. Khalifa: There is one exception in this law. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right. So,... A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: The mandatory test [2:214]  Do you expect to enter Paradise without undergoing the same tests as those before you? They suffered hardships and adversity, and were so shaken up, that the messenger ... (unintelligible), Sajjad, be quiet. (unintelligible) [2:214]  ... They suffered hardships and adversity, and were so shaken up, that the messenger and those who believed with him said, "Where is God's victory?" Indeed, God's victory is always near. Okay, so, the idea here is to worship God alone, no matter what happens. Under all circumstances. It's a matter of knowledge. You, you can see the conclusion that God is One, and He's the only Master, He's the only One that benefits or harms. He's the only One who controls the minds and hearts of the people around you. He makes them love you, or hate you, or care about you, or don't care. And with this knowledge, it doesn't matter what happens, adversity or happiness, it's, it's a fixed definite knowledge. And you know that, it doesn't matter what happens. So, also, we are here for the test. And God wants to be proud of you, and wants to show you off to the angels, and say, look at My servants. He or she worships Me no matter what happens, without ever seeing Me. And this is the whole idea of our existence. And the end of the verse says, [2:214]  ... Indeed, God's victory is always near. It must be noted also here that after their tests, there is a final test. After the final test, there is absolutely, there is nothing but kingship on earth, as God promises, when you come to the conclusion that you worship God alone. And it takes a long time, the road is long and hard. It's a continuous struggle. But there will come a time when you are perfect worshipper of God alone. Then, there is no hardship. And we can see this in Sura 24:55. These are some of the verses that we must remember all the time. Page 243. The Great Promise. It says, [24:55] GOD promises those ... Verse 55. Page 243. [24:55] GOD promises those among you who believe and work righteousness, that He will make them kings on earth, as He did for those before them, and that He will establish for them their religion that He chose for them, and that He will substitute security in place of their fears. All this because they worship Me alone, without idolizing anything besides Me. If anyone disbelieve after this, then these are the wicked. (unintelligible), come and sit next to daddy. And Sajjad, sit next to mommy. Then, we'll have no noise. Now, Jamila is free to roam there. See this, this promise is true. Now, do you remember Job? Job had lots of hardship, adversity. But once he passed the test, he recovered, his health recovered, he recovered his family, and even twice as much. He recovered his wealth, and twice as much. So, he was under the test for as long as he needed to be tested, to prove himself. And the same is true with us. Also, we must think of adversity as a cleansing and polishing process. When you join the Oneness of God alone, you expect some trouble at the beginning. Because you're cleansing all the past sins, all the past errors. And this can be cleansed only by paying for them, in this world. So, all the adversity that you have at the beginning, you come, you come join this mosque, you're gonna have 5 or 10 years of adversity. And this is because it's a polishing process. Polishing, you know how polishing goes? They take a piece of rock, and they put it in polishing machine. Very noisy. Chipping off pieces. But then, what comes out is a beautiful gem. And that's what, what will come out after you go through the polishing process. Polishing is not easy. So, what I'.  saying is that there is a final test. Also, if we look up Sura 65, Dr. Khalifa: verse 3 and 4. A man: (unintelligible) A man: What verse is that again? Dr. Khalifa: The verse is 4 and 5. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Page 401. Page 401. Verse 2. That's what verse 2 at the end of it. It says, [65:2]  ... Whoever observes righteousness towards God, He will create an exit for him, An exit from every problem [65:3]  And provide for him whence he never expects. ... When you observe God, you sacrifice a job or a source of income, strictly for the sake of God, He will provide for you whence you never expect, and you better believe it. Sura, page 401. The end of verse 2. This is the verse I want you to remember. [65:2]  ... Whoever observes righteousness towards God, He will create an exit for him, [65:3]  And provide for him whence he never expects. ... [65:3]  ... Anyone who trusts in GOD, God will suffice him. God always carries out His decisions. ... You have come to the conclusion that God is the King, the Absolute Ruler of the universe. And He will carry out His promises and His decisions. If you just, you just have to believe it. You must have absolute confidence in it. Tomorrow, there is a mandatory law, insurance law. And we have, quite a few of us have decided that we have insurance with God. But if you are with God, you have the best insurance. And you just have to believe that, that nothing will happen to you when you have insurance with God. This, this is the insurance, the difference between the insurance companies, and God's insurance is that in God's insurance, you don't have anything happen to you, to your car, to your health. With the, with the insurance companies, you will have the accidents, and the insurance company will pay for you. You have the agony of the insurance, of the accident, and the inconvenience of losing the car value, or having an operation. And the company will pay. But you just have to have the confidence that when you have insurance with God, nothing will happen to you. Also, you must know that if God wants to get you, He'll get you, whether you have insurance or not. Cause God says, they cannot escape from Me. That's what He said. You deserve a pinch, or a little accident, or a little sickness, you can't get away, not by an insurance company. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: This, how about when you registered a car (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: When you have to, then you have to. We will not buy insurance unless we have to. But, but it appears that God is already taking care of us, because the law enforcement people, the prosecutors, are all protesting the law, and they are making an official case out of it to, they say, they will not enforce it. They don't, they don't want to enforce it. So, I called the Civil Liberties Union myself, and I told them this contradicts our religious beliefs, and everything, and they didn't do anything about it. So, we will not buy insurance until we have to. Because the Quran says, if you have to eat pork, or drink wine, or do anything, if you have to, without being malicious or deliberate, then you're not committing a sin. But what I'm saying is, when God says, and provide for you whence you never expect, you must, you must know that. You must have that confidence. If you have the slightest doubt, it will not work. And this insurance business, we, we're in it, we've been in it for a long time. I mean, we've had that conviction to the extent, I told you about our friend Tariq, when the guy says, "what insurance? Who's your insurance? Where?" And he said, "I have insurance with God. (unintelligible) His phone number." He didn't, he just, he didn't, he wasn't thinking, I mean, it was the natural question coming afterwards, but then of course, he, he was stunned. Because he had a pencil in his hand, and the paper, he was ready to write the phone number. It was at (unintelligible) place, where Tariq's car was a little bit, it's the fender or bender. Somebody (unintelligible) So, [65:3]  ... God always carries out His decisions. ... He is the Absolute (unintelligible) He runs this country. It's not Ronald Reagan who runs it, or the government or any government, anywhere. God runs everything. If you go to the end of verse 4, it says, [65:4]  ... Whoever observes righteousness towards God, God will make everything easy for him. Everything will go easy for you. You will not suffer any hardship. There is absolutely no humiliation for the servants of God. You go apply for a job, and you will be the boss, because your soul takes over the place, and you will see them running to serve you. They may not realize it, but you will see it. [65:4]  ... Whoever observes righteousness towards God, God will make everything easy for him. This is God's promise as documented here, in His final message. So, we go back now to page 23, about hardship as a mandatory test. Over and over we see people who are immensely wealthy, on the TV, and they're complaining about unhappiness, Dr. Khalifa: how unhappy they, they are. A woman: Rashad. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: Is there an explanation then for (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right. All this severe problems, earthquakes, hurricanes, floods, all this are punishments, punishments and tests because all these things are absolutely controlled by God. There is a statement that will answer your question. It's in Sura, I believe 64. Let's look up 64. Sura 64 plus or minus 2 Suras. I'm gonna find it for you. Yeah, 11, verse 11. It says, [64:11]  No disaster strikes except in accordance with God's will. ... This is, this is a law. [64:11]  No disaster strikes except in accordance with God's will. ... No, no pain, no disaster, nothing happens except by personal decree from God because it is not simple. It's not, it's not easy to, to get a, a painful headache, for example. It has to be a personal decree from God, that God will sign. (unintelligible), sit here, be comfortable. Get a pillow or something. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Does this answer your question, Diana? Diana: Yes. I sort of (unintelligible) I had heard also that (unintelligible) they only expected a certain income from the people Diana: and only expected the wealth of the people Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Diana: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Well, God is angry. It's true. Every drop of water is measured. Everything in this world is measured. Every piece of ice that fell on Denver and gave them miserable time. It was measured. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A woman: Did you say also that it's almost like the Nile explaining (unintelligible) A woman: So, maybe, the richer (unintelligible) money (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, everything is planned. Every minute, the minutest detail is very carefully planned. Alhamdu Lillah. Nothing is coincidental or haphazard. Nothing. As individuals, as nations, as a world. Just think every drop of water is measured, exactly where it goes, where it's gonna fall, how many inches from an ant that's crawling on the ground. That's right. Dr. Khalifa: Ok, Carl, you wanna take recipients of charity, well, 215 to 218? Carl: Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem [2:215]  They ask you about charity: say, "Charity shall go to the parents, the relatives, the orphans, the poor, and the alien." Any righteous work you do, GOD is fully aware thereof. [2:216]  Fighting may be forced upon you, though you dislike it. But you may dislike something which is actually good for you, and you may like something which is actually bad for you. GOD knows while you do not know. [2:217]  They ask you about the desecration of the Sacred Months by fighting therein: say, "Fighting during the Sacred Months is sacrilege. But repelling the people from the path of GOD and disbelieving in Him and in the sacredness of the Sacred Mosque (Masjid), and evicting the people therefrom, are all worse sacrileges in the sight of GOD. Oppression is worse than murder." They will continue to fight you until they revert you from your religion, if they could. Those who revert from their religion, and die as disbelievers, have wasted their works in this life and in the Hereafter. They have deserved Hell, wherein they abide forever. [2:218]  As for those who believe, emigrate and strive in the cause of GOD, they have deserved God's mercy. GOD is Forgiver, Merciful. There's two different subjects here. 215 talks about the charity, and it tells us specifically that the charity first goes to those that are closest to us, to those that we're most responsible for, our parents and our relatives. And the next are those that, that really need economic help or don't have someone else to rely on, the orphans and the poor and then the alien. Carl: And... Dr. Khalifa: So, this is a carefully, when the, we, we are given the details of how charity should be distributed. It first goes to the parents if they need it. If they don't need it, then to your relatives. In other words, each takes care of his own. And if each one takes care of his own, there will be no misery in the world. If the relatives are rich, then you find orphans, children, children who have no parents, one or two parents are gone, Dr. Khalifa: and then any poor people and then the alien, so, in this world. Carl: So, any righteous work you do, GOD is fully aware of it. And it seems that charity is more than just economic help, it can be any kind of help, I mean, any righteousness of doing what is right in this world toward other people even for simply politeness or anything we try to do to make the the world better, treat the other people as we'd like to be treated or, if we're merciful toward the people around us, then God is, it's because we want to express God's mercy. We want, we desire God's forgiveness and God's mercy, and these qualities in by showing our appreciation and the desire for them to be expressed Carl: through the world around us. Martha: (unintelligible) Carl: Martha Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) from another town (unintelligible) A woman: How about E.T.? Dr. Khalifa: People are passing, passing by. Carl: And the next subject is on fighting, which I take to mean basically in a war type of situation, though it may be, well, when we think of fighting, we think of taking up arms of, of viole. ce rather than simply argument or both of them. So, at another level, it could be simply not giving in to, to any kind of oppressions, Carl: which may be economic or political or social, but... Dr. Khalifa: No, I, you know, I have two quick issues here. The only, there's only one reason in Quran for fighting, and has to do with the freedom to worship God alone. That's it. There's absolutely no other reason for fighting. Only if it's gonna interfere with your freedom of practicing the worship of God alone. And oppression meaning trying to impose any, any view, religious view on you, or to prevent you from practicing your religion. Throughout the Quran, the reason, the only reason for fighting. There's, fighting may be imposed upon you. Like somebody comes and says, "Hey, don't pray." "You cannot pray." Dr. Khalifa: They issue a law that you cannot pray. Carl: But if, if your country gets into war with another country and you're required to go and fight, Carl: like you're drafted or anything? Dr. Khalifa: No, you don't fight because of land. If you're drafted, ... A man: No, no, you can't (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the other country is here to make you not believe in God, A man: Yeah, if they are attacking us, ... Dr. Khalifa: like if Russia comes to invade this country for the purpose of turning everybody into an atheist, then that's in the cause of God. The only fighting is in the cause of God. It must be in the cause of God. So, whatever, whatever the, there are unforeseeable reasons or circumstances. But fighting for land, or because of borders, or because of country, it's all a waste of life. Dr. Khalifa: And because God did not create these borders. He didn't create visas and passports. A man: What if you're forced to defend yourself and somebody else wants to drive you away from your, your own land? A man: You have to fight, also. Or you just, you know, run away. Dr. Khalifa: Well, the self... Dr. Khalifa: The self defense. But it, it isn't because of God.  It is... Dr. Khalifa: to think about it. A man: Yeah. Yeah. A man: I mean, if they, what it says about evicting you from your houses, or you evict them from where they evicted you. A man: You do not (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: [2:191]  ... evict them whence they evicted you. ... Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A man: You know, if they're simply fighting not, they're not perceiving religious reasons, they're probably perceiving grabbing land, or political differences. Dr. Khalifa: Did we, did we go through the rules of war yet? Because that will explain it more. A woman: 190. It's... Dr. Khalifa: Did we go through that? Dean Majul: About aggression. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yeah, we did. Yeah, we did. Dean Majul: You spoke of aggression. That wars are only justified, all wars must be defensive. And we discussed that earlier. Dr. Khalifa: Self-defense, yeah. Dean Majul: And offense. Dr. Khalifa: But in those rules of war, they say, [2:191]  ... Do not fight them at the Sacred Mosque (Masjid), unless they attack you therein. ... If we're sitting here worshipping God alone, and somebody comes and says, hey, you can't, Dr. Khalifa: you can't practice Islam here, or something, you know, this is where we have to fight them. A woman: I want to hear everybody cry. Dean Majul: You'd be surprised. Anything can happen. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A woman: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: We just, we happen to have a formidable army around this building anyway, as you know. Brother Abdullah is visiting us from Seattle. And he's, he's one rare person who comes because he, he, he were leery of the Hadith. So, he came to see us just because we believe in the Quran alone. But anyway, what I wanna tell you is that people try to deface this sign out there, and, and, twice, because they felt miserable every time. So, there are invisible forces around us here. We don't need to do anything. This age is an age of mental, mental debate, rather than swords and fighting. Dr. Khalifa: Anyway, we can't fight because of land, over land or money, or, and, unless you're attacked, anyway. A man: What about (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Well, joining is something, and fighting is something else. Dr. Khalifa: I mean, they join the armed forces, but they don't fight, but it's like a job. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: It's a waste of life. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: The job is a means of supporting your, to earn an honest living. A man: If you, if you join anything and you simply earn a living for something, Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: if it's part of an institution that's involved in something, it's not... A man: Yeah, but you don't know what else is involved. Dr. Khalifa: Well, you don't earn your living selling liquor, for example, which is breaking God's law. A man: But suppose you went to work... Dr. Khalifa: But he's asking about joining the armed forces. Dr. Khalifa: Well, if you joined the armed forces and there's no war, it's just like any job. A man: But suppose your government gets in a war with another country and you... Dr. Khalifa: That's when you have to make a decision whether this is because of God or not. Because of God, you pick a fight? Dr. Khalifa: If it's in the cause of God, that will do it. A man: Well, suppose you're working for a big company and they're producing something that, you know, like, it's... Well, or, say, napalm or chemical weapons. A man: You know, maybe you're not directly involved in the manufacturing, but you (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: That's, if there is no war, it's perfectly all right, because the Quran says, prepare for war, prepare the maximum power that you have. Be prepared. But war itself is, as, aggression is forbidden. That's breaking God's law. So, joining the armed forces or making weapons or anything that is not war is perfectly all right. Dr. Khalifa: If it is war, then you have to make a decision if it is in the cause of God or not. A man: So, it's okay to have nuclear arms race? Dr. Khalifa: That's right. You bet. Dr. Khalifa: If we, if we didn't have nuclear weapons in this country, you can be sure Russia will be here in a week. A man: What, what about the idea that, Dr. Khalifa: Effectively over. A man: what about the idea that we trusted God to protect us? Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but God orders you to make weapons. A man: But if the, you know, if we really, it's like the insurance (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: No. A man: If you really trusted God, He, He sent you weapons, Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: the bombs. Dr. Khalifa: When you trust in God A man: why would He liberate them in the sky? Dr. Khalifa: When you trust in God, you follow His commandments. One of His commandments is, prepare the maximum power you can muster. This is a, a verse in the Quran. You wanna see it? (unintelligible) I think it's in Sura 9. But I wanna refer to the, the index. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, I, I meant to talk to you about this once before because you said, trust in God and don't make any weapons. A man: Preemptive strike which is attacking first. Dr. Khalifa: Hello, hello, hello. A man: They call it preemptive strike. They didn't say attacking. Dean Majul: And that's 4:41. Dean Majul: 39:41 A man: (unintelligible) Dean Majul: I'm not so sure. A man: It's a matter of strategy. A man: Sura 9 Dean Majul: Sura 9, verse 41 Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, no, there is a more straightforward verse. Dean Majul: It says, Dean Majul: [9:41] ... readily mobilize, ... A man: It's page 112. Dr. Khalifa: There's a straightforward commandment to prepare the maximum power. A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Sura 8, verse 60. Sura 8, verse 60. This is a commandment, you shall. It says, you, this is page 124, verse 6 0, 60. [8:60]  You shall prepare for them all the force and equipment you can muster in order to deter the enemies of GOD, and your enemies, as well as others you are not aware of while GOD knows them. Anything you expend in the cause of GOD will be repaid to you, without the least injustice. It's a very straightforward commandment, it says, prepare. You must, you must always have a deterring force. Dr. Khalifa: So, it is, you trust in God, but you follow what He says. You know, it's not... A man: It says, 20 can defeat 200. And take your time. Dr. Khalifa: That's right. A man: There was an early battle in which the, the Muslims were greatly outnumbered. Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah. A man: And, and there was a chance (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: That's, that's another one, that's another one. Dr. Khalifa: But the battle of Badr, look it up, look it up in the encyclopedia Britannica. A man: Badr. Dr. Khalifa: And they looked at it from the strategic point of view, the logistic point of view, the, the numbers of needs (unintelligible) And they tried to analyze it militarily and this doesn't make sense. Dr. Khalifa: The Muslims defeated the disbelievers. Dean Majul: Also, the battle of Yarmuk, when they beat, when they beat the Byzantine, Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Dean Majul: they were outnumbered. Dean Majul: And in the battle of Qadisiyyah against the Persians, Dr. Khalifa: That's right. Dean Majul: the best army in the world. Dr. Khalifa: Now those were... Dean Majul: Full Persians. Dr. Khalifa: Those were actual battles where the Muslims were outnumbered 10 to 1. Dr. Khalifa: But we're told in Quran that the angels were fighting beside Muslims. A man: We have enough weapons now to destroy 200 (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Good. A man: Do we need to go anywhere? Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Well, they are, they are, they are having the practical means to nullify (unintelligible), Laser (unintelligible) A man: And they can't satellite (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: But, well, back to Carl. Let's listen to Carl. Carl: [2:191]  ... Oppression is worse than murder. ... Dr. Khalifa: instead of the soul. Carl: It's... It's an attempt to manipulate somebody's mind and heart. And... To Carl: make other people follow one's own material desires. And Carl: whoever is (unintelligible) Dean Majul: May I add, may I add, add something to that as a revision? Dean Majul: It's not just that they're trying to change your mind. Dean Majul: But to make you revert to a situation of unbelief. Carl: Yes. Dean Majul: In other words, the Muslims now have come, they've arrived at the truth. All right? Dean Majul: And for you to go from truth back to unbelief, Carl: Yes. Dean Majul: that is what our Ustaz is saying is Dr. Khalifa: Murder of the soul. Dean Majul: Murder of the soul. It's not a matter of just changing your belief. Dean Majul: But it's going back to unbelief, which is terrible. Carl: Yeah. Dean Majul: And Quran says many times, once you have the belief, many people will try to let you revert to unbelief. So, that is a, it's terrible because the punishment for, the punishment for unbelief after belief is greater than just unbelief from beginning to end. Dean Majul: I think Quran says that too, a few times. Carl: Yeah, it says it in the next... Dean Majul: Does it say so? I'm sorry. Carl: It says, [2:217]  ... Those who revert from their religion, and die as disbelievers, have wasted their works in this life and in the Hereafter. They have deserved Hell, wherein they abide forever. [2:218]  And those who believe, emigrate and strive in the cause of GOD, ... So, it's telling I think that if we are oppressed and we can't fight them, it's better to get up and leave and go someplace where we can follow or obey God's commandments. To write, to, I guess it's telling us to fight if we can, if not to, to try to get away from that situation. Carl: [2:218]  ... GOD is Forgiver, Merciful. Dean Majul: Now, this, this is very interesting verse because people have pointed out many times. I think they, they interpret this verse out of context. "How can oppression or persecution be worse than the murder?" They say. But actually, if you read the whole thing, I think what it means is this: Dean Majul: In the long run, going to Hell Dr. Khalifa: is a lot worse. Dean Majul: It's worse than the murder. Dean Majul: I think oppression, I think...